# Elankumaran Sivasubramaniam

### Software Engineer

Goal-oriented Web Developer brings strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Use various web design packages to develop custom-crafted, customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of user experience, usability and speed over more than 2 years for multiple users. Well-versed in developing custom React, Node, Mongo DB, Express projects.



siva98kumarane@gmail.com

0763762180

Jaffna, Sri lanka

•

elankumaran98.github.io/Portfolio/

linkedin.com/in/elankumaran- in sivasubramaniam

github.com/Elankumaran98

### **EDUCATION**

# Reading for B.Sc (Hons) in Software Engineering

University Of Kelaniya

02/2019 - 06/2023

GPA:-2.82

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Web Developer

Freelancer

10/2023 - Present

#### Tasks

- Created a tool to efficiently fetch IMDb IDs, improving content retrieval for movie-related projects.
- Assisted in the creation of detailed project specifications, outlining key requirements for successful implementation of client objectives.
- Provided front-end development support, creating visually appealing designs that aligned with brand standards.

# Associate Software Engineer

Techscrolll

04/2023 - 09/2023

Front End Development in Delivery
App

Colombo 08

#### Tasks

- API Integration for map features.
- Maintained accurate documentation of code changes, ensuring smooth handoffs between team members.

Contact: Sunimal - 0713257942

## Software Engineer intern

**Gypzeez** 

09/2021 - 02/2022

Colombo

Part of the E commerce site development

- Developed and maintained React-based application(Shopping App), ensuring a high level of functionality and performance.
- Implemented Redux for state management in that project.

Contact: Kiruththikan - 0774949979

### **SKILLS**



#### **PROJECTS**

Pizza Shopping Web App (12/2023 - 02/2024)

- Use Stipe for payment intergration.
- Adding Search Engine Optimization.
- Use redux for state management.

POS Web App (02/2023 - 03/2023)

- Generate PDF Bills
- Use Ant Design For Style

#### Hotflix Admin dashboard (10/2020 - 12/2023)

- Build Admin dashboard Using MERN Stack
- Working on IMDB movie fetching API
- Updating Code old version to new Version

# ProHub (Project management application) (02/2022 - 07/2022)

- Developed reusable UI components to reduce development time(React).
- Used Agile methodology for software development and worked in a fast-paced environment.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Tamil

English

Professional Working Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Limited Working Proficiency

#### **INTERESTS**

Sinhala

Playing Cricket

**Watching Cricket**